Mobile: +91 97393 888 90 | E-mail: venkatmp16@gmail.com Online Portfolio: *Click here*

Summary

A leading Graphic designer specializing in information architecture, usability, and UI design for Web-based consumer and business applications, workflows, online marketing, and social media with 8+ years of experience, extensive background in long-term client relationships, wireframing, user testing, and rapid prototyping; well-versed in user-centered design and agile methods; able to help shape the big picture and drill into the details.

Work Experience

Senior Designer in SmartOwner Servies (P) Ltd, Bangalore October 2015 - Present

Graphic Design Supervisor at Flatworld Solutions (P) Ltd, Bangalore March 2012 – September 2015

Sr. Web & Graphic Designer at 2Adpro Media Solutions (P) Ltd, Chennai August 2011 – March 2012

Graphic Designer at Macmillan Publishing Solutions (P) Ltd, Bangalore May 2010 – June 2011

Skill Sets

Concept skills: Soft Skills:

Graphic Design
Visual & Interaction Design
User Experience (UX)
User Interface (UI)
W3 Web standards
Customer Focus
Attention to Detail
Deadline-Oriented
Handles Rejection

» People & project Management

Designing Softwares

Multimedia tools: Business tools:

» Adobe Photoshop CC
» Adobe Illustrator CC
» Adobe InDesign CC
» MS Excel 2011
» MS Word 2011
» Quark X Press
» Outlook

» Dreamweaver CC

" Dreamweaver CC
" Premiere Pro CC
" Fireworks CC
" CorelDraw
" HTML5 & CSS3
Other tools:
" Taco HTML Edit
" FileZilla FTP Client
" Acrobat 9 Professional

Professional Experience

Create Visual designs that effectively communicate product functions and enhance the user experience, including the design and production of screen layouts, User interface elements and visual communications.

Developing creative ideas and concepts, choosing the appropriate media and style to meet the client's objectives. Demanding creative flair, up-to-date knowledge of industry software and a professional approach to time, costs and deadlines.

Developing design briefs by gathering information and data through research.

Venkatesh MP

Mobile: +91 97393 888 90 | E-mail: venkatmp16@gmail.com Online Portfolio: *Click here*

Educational Qualifications

MBA in Information Systems (MBA-IS) 68% VV Puram College of Science, Annamalai University, Bangalore. *Year of completion: (2012-2014)*

Bachelor of Visual Communication (Bsc) 73% VV Puram College of Science, Annamalai University, Bangalore. *Year of completion: (2009-2012)*

Personal Details

Sex: Male

DOB: 16 Nov 87

Languages Known: English, Tamil, Kannada, Malayalam & Hindi

Marital Status: Married

Contact Details

9A/Radiant Enclave,

Banjara Layout, Horamavu,

Bangalore - 560 043

Mobile: +91 97393 88890 | E-mail: venkateshmp16@gmail.com

Declaration

I do hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated herein above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date:

Place: Ponvenkatesh M